Hi, my name is Lauren and today I am going to discuss how to spike thick hair.
Spiking thick hair because of the heaviness of it will start when you first get your hair cut.
There is something called thinning shears or notching shears and they actually have these little serrated edges on the one side.
So it actually just simply removes bulk from the hair.
If you have your stylist use these, once you are trying to style your hair and spike it, it will remove some of that weight and make your job easier.
Now, once you are at home what you are going to do is use a blow dryer and blow your hair straight up as far up as you can get it.
There are heavier products that you want to use.
Some are a little bit more thread like and kind of help it attach.
Also you can use very hard gels.
You want something with strong hold in order to really keep the spikes up and to work with that little bit of that coarser, fuller hair style.
So you can kind of spike everything up using these hard hold gels.
You can also use hard hold hair sprays in order to get them to stay.
There is also a corporation called Spiker's Gel which make a bit of the stronger hold gels in order to help maintain and help coarser hair and fuller and thicker hair stand up and actually spike.
And that is how to spike coarse hair.